

🛮 (+91) 991-516-8329 | 🔀 binnykaur96@gmail.com | 🔏 binny-kaur.netlify.app | 🛅 binny-kaur

"Be the change that you want to see in the world." - Mohandas Gandhi

## Summary.

I have 3+ years of experience working in semi - government and startup environments across domains of supply chain operations and project management. A quick learner with proven analytical skills and high sense of responsibility, positive attitude and ability to build an effective working relationship within a team and across functions.

### Skills

- · Supply chain process excellence
- · Business Analysis
- **Sourcing & Procurement**
- **Business Requirement Documentation**
- SAP-MM
- · Relational databases: MySQL

- **Microsoft Office**
- **Project Management**
- **Vendor Management**
- **Warehouse System Design**
- BI Tools: Tableau, PowerBI
- Canva Poster/ Newsletter Tool

# Work Experience \_

#### Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Noida, India

**BUSINESS PROCESS ANALYST** Oct. 2021 - Present

- · Refactoring and analyzing complex supply chain data and publishing insightful reports to the client.
- Tracking medical goods in transit in the reverse chain for our client Philips in American countries.
- Evaluating exceptional cases that account for error or delay in inbound of goods in the warehouse.

**Grofers India Pvt. Ltd.** Gurugram, India

ASSISTANT MANAGER Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2021

- · Handled pan India day to day operations for process improvements, pilferage reduction and cost optimization.
- Removed redundant aggregation centres in the supply chain, saving cost by upto 40% from the existing metrics.
- Setup process improvement guidelines and documented those SOPs for successful rollout in pan India operations.
- · Created dashboards to publish item missing, perfect orders and complaints metrics for each zonal region.
- Successful in introduction of electric fleet in last mile delivery of orders. Thus reducing logistics cost by 50% in various regions and also making
- Processed technology integration requests from Infra team for successful launch of new store.
- Developed incentive program for manpower involved in order delivery process which resulted 9% reduction in customer complaints.

Vedanta Resources Ltd. Chhattisgarh, India

ASSISTANT MANAGER Aug. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- · Managed procurement of specific categories of spares for various strategic business units under the company.
- · Ensured compliance while upholding the terms and conditions as mentioned in purchase orders with third party logistics (3PL) suppliers and vendors
- · Ensured partner agreement adherence through appropriate contract management and ongoing partnership with the legal team.
- Established supplier base and performance development metrics to form strategic relationships with the suppliers.
- · Published monthly procurement reports highlighting slow and fast moving spares to help manage inventory.

## **Education**

### Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology

Patiala, India

B.E. IN ELECTRONICS INSTRUMENTATION AND CONTROL ENGINEERING

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2018

- · Organized technical events, workshops as a member of the Electronics Instrumentation and Control Engineering club.
- · Helped organize university fundraisers for blood donation camps, eco-club, exceeding expected donation amounts by 25% through the use of diverse marketing channels and gathering options.
- · Organized five-plus social events as a vice-president of Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology Rotaract Club.

## Achievements

- Successfully launched the Electric fleet operations for last mile delivery of orders at Grofers. Grofers took its first step toward sustainable ecommerce deliveries through this project. Achieved a 60% reduction in intransit order damage and reduced customer complaints by 30% through this initiative.
- Acted as lead in an ad film for Grofers inhouse cosmetic brand Orange Something. This promotion film raised sales of the product by 20%.
- · Sourced indigenious vendor for Boron Hardener, key ingredient required to increase the conductivity of aluminum rods, which drive almost 30% revenue of finished products offered by BALCO. This partnership with the vendor resulted in a tangible benefit of 1Cr to the firm.